Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Edward Lear miscellaneous drawings, 1849-1866 (MS Typ 55.14): Guide.
Edward Lear miscellaneous drawings,
1849-1866.
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
MS Typ 55.14
Lear, Edward, 1812-1888.
2 boxes (.5 linear ft.)
Drawings, poems, proofs, landscapes, portraits and other items by the English poet and artist Edward Lear.
Unless otherwise noted, gift of Philip Hofer, 1942.
Access requires permission of curator.
Lear was an English poet and artist.
Arranged in rough alphabetical order by title.
Includes Lear's nonsense drawings, autograph manuscript drafts of the nonsense poems and nonsense alphabet, drawings with verse, and proofs for The nonsense alphabet and other works. Also includes a few landscape drawings, a portrait of an unidentified man, self-portraits, and a portrait photograph of Lear, among other items.
The majority of Lear landscape drawings are listed in MS Typ 55.11, MS Typ 55.26, and TypDr 805.L513
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. A bumbel[!] B: drawing., (1); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Armchairia comfortabilis: drawing., (2); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Bassia palealensis: drawing., (3); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Bluebottlia buzztilentia: drawing., (4); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Bubblia blowpipia: drawing., (5); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. [Burnt] sienna and indian red: drawing., (6); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Crabbia horrida: drawing., (7); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Designs for a monogram, J.E.B.: drawing., (8); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Eastern landscape: pen-and-ink., (9); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Discovery of a large moth: drawing., (10); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Knutmigrata simplice: drawing., (11); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Landscape: brush and ink drawing., (12); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Manypeeplia upsidownia: drawing., (13); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Untitled: pencil drawing., (14); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Sketches made in India: pencil drawing., (15); 2s.(2p.)
  - Page 1
  - Page 2
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Phattfacia stupenda: drawing., (16); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Portrait of an unidentified man: drawing., (17); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Puffia leatherbellowsa: drawing., (18); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Queeriflora babyöides: drawing., (19); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Self- portrait: drawing. Apl. 21. 1849., (20); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Self- portrait cut from the end of a letter: drawing., (21); 1s.(2p.)
  - Recto
  - Verso
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Self- portrait? cut from the end of a letter: drawing., (22); 1s.(2p.)
  - Recto
  - Verso
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Self- portrait on stilts: drawing., (23); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Smalltoothcombia domestica: drawing., (24); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The absolutely abstemious ass: drawing., (25); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The biscuit tree: drawing., (26); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The clomjombimbilious tree: drawing., (27); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The clothes-brush tree: drawing., (28); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The comfortable confidential cow: drawing., (29); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The courtship of the Yonghy-Bonghy-Bò: drawing., (30); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The dish tree: drawing., (31); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The dolomphious duck: drawing., (32); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The fork tree: drawing., (33); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The goodnatured grey gull: drawing., (34); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The hasty higgeldipiggledy hen: drawing., (35); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The jumblies: proof. 1s., (36)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The kite tree: drawing., (37); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The rabbit tree: drawing., (38); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The two old bachelors: drawing., (39); 1s.(2p.)
  - Recto
  - Verso
  - Recto mount
  - Verso mount
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The zigzag zealous zebra: drawing., (40); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. [There is a young lady, whose nose]: drawing., (41); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. [There was an old man who supposed]: drawing., (42); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old person of Rye, and The owl and the pussy cat: drawings., (43); 2s., mounted together.
  - Recto
  - Verso
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. [There was an old person of] Shoreham: drawing., (44); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Tureenia ladlecum: drawing., (45); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Umbrellifera: drawing; Kendal, Aug 20th 1836., (46); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Blackbirds & ferns: drawing and verse., (47); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Bonnets & legs: drawing and verse., (48); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Chimnies & wings: drawing and verse., (49); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Cutlets & eyes: drawing and verse., (50); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Eagles & pears: drawing and verse., (51); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Gruel & prawns: drawing and verse., (52); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Herons & sweeps: drawing and verse., (53); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Houses & kings: drawing and verse., (54); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Houses & kings: drawing and verse., (55); 1s.(1p.)
  - Recto
  - Verso
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Hurdles & mumps: drawing and verse., (56); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Lobsters & owls: drawing and verse., (57); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Mitres & beams: drawing and verse., (58); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Nonsense alphabet: A was some ants: drawing and verse., (59); 4s.(4p.)
  - Page 1
  - Page 2
  - Page 3
  - Page 4
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Pancakes & fins: drawing and verse., (60); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Puddings & beams: drawing and verse., (61); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Rainbows & knives: drawing and verse., (62); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Rainbows & wives: drawing and verse., (63); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Ribands & pigs: drawing and verse., (64); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Saucers & tops: drawing and verse., (65); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Scissors & fowls: drawing and verse., (66); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Sofas & bees: drawing and verse., (67); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Tadpoles & tops: drawing and verse., (68); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Tea urns & pews: drawing and verse., (69); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Teapots & quails: drawing and verse., (70); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The owl and the pussy cat, stanza 3: drawing and verse., (71); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was a young lady of Chertsey: drawing and verse., (72); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man in a pew: drawing and verse., (73); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man of Blackheath: drawing and verse., (74); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man of Dumblayne: drawing and verse., (75); 1s.(2p.)
  - Recto
  - Verso
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man of Dunluce: drawing and verse., (76); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man of Melrose: drawing and verse., (77); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man of Siberia: drawing and verse., (78); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man of Thames Ditton: drawing and verse., (79); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. [There was an] old man on a hill: drawing and verse., (80); 1s.(2p.)
  - Recto
  - Verso
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man who said "Hum!": drawing and verse., (81); 1s.(2p.)
  - Recto
  - Verso
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man on whose nose: drawing and verse., (82); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man with a beard: drawing and verse., (83); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man with a nose: drawing and verse., (84); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old person of Philae: drawing and verse., (85); 1s.(2p.)
  - Recto
  - Verso
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old person of Spain: drawing and verse., (86); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old person who said: drawing and verse., (87); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Thistles & moles: drawing and verse., (88); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Trumpets & guns: drawing and verse., (89); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Volumes & pigs: drawing and verse., (90); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Wafers & bears: drawing and verse., (91); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Watches & oaks: drawing and verse., (92); 1s.(1p.)
- [Lear, Edward, 1812-1888]. Once I had a mucous membrane...: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [San Remo, undated]., (93); 1s.(1p.)
  Unfinished draft of a nonsense poem.
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Calico pie: proofs. 4s., (94)
  - Page 1
  - Page 2
  - Page 3
  - Page 4
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. [Two parrots]: lithograph proof., (95)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Mr. and Mrs. Spikky Sparrow: proofs., (96); 2s.
  - Page 1
  - Page 2
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Nonsense alphabet: A. was an area arch: proofs and illustrations., (97); 26s.
  Letters A-O are accompanied by proof of letterpress text; P-Z are illustrations only.
  - Letter A.
  - Letter B.
  - Letter C.
  - Letter D.
  - Letter E.
  - Letter F.
  - Letter G.
  - Letter H.
  - Letter I.
  - Letter J.
  - Letter K.
  - Letter L.
  - Letter M.
  - Letter N.
  - Letter O.
  - Letter P.
  - Letter Q.
  - Letter R.
  - Letter S.
  - Letter T.
  - Letter U.
  - Letter V.
  - Letter W.
  - Letter X.
  - Letter Y.
  - Letter Z.
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The broom, the shovel, the poker and the tongs: proofs., (98); 2s.
  - Sheet 1.
  - Sheet 2.
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Proof: The courtship of the Yonghy-Bonghy-Bò: proof., (99); 1s.
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The daddy long-legs and the fly: proofs., (100); 2s.
  - Sheet 1.
  - Sheet 2.
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The duck and the kangaroo: proofs., (101); 4s.
  - Sheet 1.
  - Sheet 2.
  - Sheet 3.
  - Sheet 4.
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The history of the seven families of the lake Pipple-Popple: proofs., (102); 16s.
  - Sheet 1.
  - Sheet 2.
  - Sheet 3.
  - Sheet 4.
  - Sheet 5.
  - Sheet 6.
  - Sheet 7.
  - Sheet 8.
  - Sheet 9.
  - Sheet 10.
  - Sheet 11.
  - Sheet 12.
  - Sheet 13.
  - Sheet 14.
  - Sheet 15.
  - Sheet 16.
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The owl and the pussy cat and The seven families of Lake Pipple-Popple: proofs., (103)
  Proof (rubbing) of 1 block for Owl and the pussy cat and 2 for The seven families....
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The nutcrackers and the sugar-tongs: proof., (104); 1s.
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The owl and the pussy cat: proofs., (105); 3s.
  - Sheet 1.
  - Sheet 2.
  - Sheet 3.
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The pelican chorus: proof., (106); 1s.
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The story of the four little children: proofs., (107); 15s.
  - Sheet 1.
  - Sheet 2.
  - Sheet 3.
  - Sheet 4.
  - Sheet 5.
  - Sheet 6.
  - Sheet 7.
  - Sheet 8.
  - Sheet 9.
  - Sheet 10.
  - Sheet 11.
  - Sheet 12.
  - Sheet 13.
  - Sheet 14.
  - Sheet 15.
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The table and the chair: proofs., (108); 3s.
  - Sheet 1.
  - Sheet 2.
  - Sheet 3.
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old lady of Prague (1, with autograph inscription) There was a young lady of Poole (1) There was a young girl of Majorca (1), (109)
  - There was an old lady of Prague
  - There was a young lady of Poole
  - There was a young girl of Majorca
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man of Berlin, There was an old man of the West, and There was an old person of Tartary: proofs., (110)
  One proof for each title.
  - There was an old man of Berlin
  - There was an old man of the West
  - There was an old person of Tartary
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man of Coblenz, There was an old man of Leghorn, and There was a young lady of Hull: proofs., (111)
  - There was an old man of Coblenz
  - There was an old man of Leghorn
  - There was a young lady of Hull
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man of Corfu, There was an old man of Vesuvius, and There was an old person of Rheims: proofs., (112)
  - There was an old man of Corfu
  - There was an old man of Vesuvius
  - There was an old person of Rheims
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man of Dundee, There was an old lady whose folly, and There was an old man of Calcutta: proofs., (113)
  One proof for each title, except 2 for ... Calcutta.
  - There was an old man of Dundee
  - There was an old lady whose folly
  - There was an old man of Calcutta: sheet 1
  - There was an old man of Calcutta: sheet 2
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man of Jamaica, There was an old man of the East, and There was an old man of the Coast: proofs., (114)
  - There was an old man of Jamaica
  - There was an old man of the East
  - There was an old man of the Coast
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man of Peru, There was a young lady whose eyes, There was an old man of Columbia: proofs., (115)
  One proof for each title. ...Peru includes an autograph annotation.
  - There was an old man of Peru
  - There was a young lady whose eyes
  - There was an old man of Columbia
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man of th'Abruzzi, There was an old man of Nepaul, and There was an old person of Ischia: proofs., (116)
  - There was an old man of th'Abruzzi
  - There was an old man of Nepaul
  - There was an old person of Ischia
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man of the Cape, There was an old person of Burton, and There was an old person of Ems: proofs., (117)
  One proof for each title, except 2 for ...Burton.
  - There was an old man of the Cape
  - There was an old person of Burton: proof 1
  - There was an old person of Burton: proof 2
  - There was an old person of Ems
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man of the Dee, There was an old person of Troy, and There was an old man of Marseilles: proofs., (118)
  - There was an old man of the Dee
  - There was an old person of Troy
  - There was an old man of Marseilles
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man of the Wrekin, There was an old man on whose nose, and There was a young person of Crete: proofs., (119)
  One proof for each title. ...nose also with an autograph verse.
  - There was an old man of the Wrekin
  - There was an old man on whose nose
  - There was a young person of Crete
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man of Quebec, There was a young lady of Bute, and There was an old person of Tring: proofs., (120)
  - There was an old man of Quebec
  - There was a young lady of Bute
  - There was an old person of Tring
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man of Vienna, There was an old person of Leeds, and There was an old man of the West: proofs., (121)
  - There was an old man of Vienna
  - There was an old person of Leeds
  - There was an old man of the West
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old man with an owl, There was an old man of Moldavia, and There was an old person of Hurst: proofs., (122)
  - There was an old man with an owl
  - There was an old man of Moldavia
  - There was an old person of Hurst
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old person of Anerley and There was an old man of Madras: proofs., (123)
  - There was an old person of Anerley
  - There was an old man of Madras
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old person of Cadiz, There was an old person of Basing, and There was an old man of the Isles: proofs., (124)
  - There was an old person of Cadiz
  - There was an old person of Basing
  - There was an old man of the Isles
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old person of Cheadle, There was a young lady of Wales, and There was a young lady of Welling: proofs., (125)
  One proof for each title. Both ...Wales and ... Welling have autograph inscriptions.
  - There was an old person of Cheadle
  - There was a young lady of Wales
  - There was a young lady of Welling
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old person of Mold, There was an old person of Rhodes, and There was an old man of Bohemia: proofs., (126)
  - There was an old person of Mold
  - There was an old person of Rhodes
  - There was an old man of Bohemia
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old person of Philae, There was an old man of the North, and There was an old man of the South: proofs., (127)
  - There was an old person of Philae
  - There was an old man of the North
  - There was an old man of the South
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old person of Prague, There was an old man of the Nile, and There was a young lady of Lucca: proofs., (128)
  - There was an old person of Prague
  - There was an old man of the Nile
  - There was a young lady of Lucca
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was an old person whose habits, There was an old man of Apulia, and There was a young lady of Norway: proofs., (129)
  - There was an old person whose habits
  - There was an old man of Apulia
  - There was a young lady of Norway
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was a young lady of Dorking, There was an old man of Cape Horn, and There was an old person of Ewell: proofs., (130)
  - There was a young lady of Dorking
  - There was an old man of Cape Horn
  - There was an old person of Ewell
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was a young lady of Parma, There was an old person of Sparta, and There was a young lady of Turkey; proofs., (131)
  - There was a young lady of Parma
  - There was an old person of Sparta
  - There was a young lady of Turkey
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was a young lady of Sweden, There was an old person of Chester, and There was an old man of Melrose: proofs., (132)
  One proof for for ... Melrose; 2 for ... Sweden; and 3 for ...Chester, which includes one with autograph verse.
  - There was a young lady of Sweden: proof 1
  - There was a young lady of Sweden: proof 2
  - There was an old person of Chester: proof 1
  - There was an old person of Chester: proof 2
  - There was an old person of Chester: proof 3
  - There was an old man of Melrose
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was a young lady of Troy, There was an old man of Kilkenny, and There was an old person of Buda: proofs., (133)
  - There was a young lady of Troy
  - There was an old man of Kilkenny
  - There was an old person of Buda
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was a young lady of Tyre, There was an old man of Kamschatka, and There was an old person of Gretna: proofs., (134)
  - There was a young lady of Tyre
  - There was an old man of Kamschatka
  - There was an old person of Gretna
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. There was a young lady whose nose was so long that it reached to her toes, There was an old person of Bangor, and There was a young lady of Russia: proofs., (135)
  - There was a young lady whose nose was so long that it reached to her toes
  - There was an old person of Bangor
  - There was a young lady of Russia
- [Lear, Edward, 1812-1888]. Victor Hugo: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [no place, undated]., (136); 1s.(2p.)
  Unfinished draft of poem. In French.
  Received?: 1942.
  - Recto
  - Verso
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Calico pie: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [no place, undated]., (137); 1s.(1p.)
  A nonsense poem, with drawings.
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Cold are the crabs that crawl on yonder hill: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [no place, undated]., (138); 1s.(1p.)
  A nonsense poem.
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. [Drafts of limericks and the beginning of a nonsense alphabet]: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [no place, undated]., (139); 1s.(1p.)
  - Recto
  - Verso
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. [Ornamental borders]: pen-and-ink drawings (signed with initials); [London, undated]., (140); 5s.(5p.)
  - Page 1
  - Page 2
  - Page 3
  - Page 4
  - Page 5, recto
  - Page 5, verso
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. How pleasant to know Mr. Lear: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [no place, undated]., (141); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Mr. Monkey: pen-and-ink drawing; [no place, 1875?]., (142); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. [Musical setting for A lament, by Percy Bysshe Shelley]: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [no place, undated]., (143); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. [Nonsense alphabet; beginning: A was once an apple pie]: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [no place, undated]., (144); 26s.(29p.).
  Recataloged from: MS Typ 55.11.
  - Letter A, recto
  - Letter A, verso
  - Letter B, recto
  - Letter B, verso
  - Letter C
  - Letter D
  - Letter E, recto
  - Letter E, verso
  - Letter F
  - Letter G
  - Letter H
  - Letter I
  - Letter J
  - Letter K
  - Letter L
  - Letter M
  - Letter N
  - Letter O
  - Letter P
  - Letter Q
  - Letter R
  - Letter S
  - Letter T
  - Letter U
  - Letter V
  - Letter W
  - Letter X
  - Letter Y
  - Letter Z, recto
  - Letter Z, verso
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. [Notes on his career as an artist]: autograph manuscript (unsigned); Brianza, [1886?]., (145); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. [Notes on Visits to monasteries in the Levant (1849) by Robert Curzon, 14th baron Zouche]: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [no place, undated]., (146); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. Phos: pen-and-ink drawing (signed); [no place],1875 July 15., (147); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The adventures of Mr. Lear & the Polly Pussey Bite on their way to the Ritertitle mountains: autograph manuscript (signed: 3d person); [no place], 1866 August 23., (148); 6s.(6p.)
  A story with pictures. F.4 and F. 6 of an original, 8f. wanting.
  - Page 1
  - Page 2
  - Page 3
  - Page 4
  - Page 5
  - Page 6
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The broom & the shovel, the poker and tongs: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [no place, undated]., (149); 1s.(2p.)
  - Recto
  - Verso
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The courtship of the Yonghy-Bonghy-Bò: uncorrected page-proof of text and illustrations; [no place, undated]., (150); 1s.(4p.)
  - Page 1
  - Page 2-3
  - Page 4
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The daddy long-legs and the fly: autograph manuscript (signed); [no place], 1869 October 14., (151); 1s.(2p.)
  - Recto
  - Verso
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The dong with a luminous nose: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [no place, undated]., (152); 1s.(3p.)
  Nonsense poem, with drawing.
  - Page 1
  - Page 2-3
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The duck and the kangaroo: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [no place, undated]., (153); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The little mouse lived quite close to the oven: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [Italy, undated]., (154); 1s.(1p.)
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The owl & the pussy cat: autograph manuscript (signed); Ross, Herefordshire, 1868 October 19., (155); 1s.(1p.)
  Also includes: 1 drawing of The owl, the pussycat, and the turkey.
  - The owl, the pussycat, and the turkey
  - Nonsense poem
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The pelicans: manuscript (by copyist); [no place, undated]., (156); 1s.(1p.)
  Music only.
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The pelicans: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [Italy, undated]., (157); 1s.(1p.)
  Musical setting for the poem; title and words in Lear's autograph, music by a copyist.
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The Quangle-Wangle's hat: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [no place, undated]., (158); 1s.(1p.)
  A nonsense poem, with drawing.
  - Recto
  - Recto, detail of drawing
  - Verso
- Lear, Edward, 1812-1888. The scroobious pip: autograph manuscript (unsigned); [no place, undated]., (159); 1s.(2p.)
  A nonsense poem, with drawing; on the verso is a page from a journal of a tour in Corsica, 1800? April 16-17.
  - Recto
  - Verso